Aisle Project 1 Answer

⁃ While I've had limited experience with DB and backend, I thought about this problem statement
⁃ First thing that came to my mind was since "likes" count were to be updated at a fixed time daily, we would need an automation script to carry that out.
⁃ turns out that script is called "Cron"
⁃ we can write a cron script according to county's time zone to update the likes

⁃ Now regarding scalability
⁃ So since we have users around the whole world, updating just a part of DB for a specific time zone might cause DB-Locks (where DB is locked until the task is completed)
⁃ Now DB-partitioning can prevent locks condition 
⁃ For example say our Aisle DB has 10 billion rows
⁃ Out of which 3 billion is American 
⁃ 5 billion is asians
⁃ 2 billion is some other region
⁃ So DB partitioning (around continents say) will allow us to lock DB when updating max-to-max 5 billion users. which will result is reduced operation time and locks will be applied for less time too
